<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thailand on Gerald Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/tags/thailand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thailand on Gerald Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://geraldnguyen.github.io/tags/thailand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AFF Cup needs VAR</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/aff-cup-needs-var/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/aff-cup-needs-var/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thailand comfortably beat Vietnam 1–0 on home soil to seal a 3–2 aggregate win and retain the crown for yet another 2 years. Theerathon Bunmathan was voted the most valuable player of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What impressed me most about Theerathon was not his consistent and superb performance but what he said after the match. Theerathon reportedly said that he wanted VAR to be available in future AFF cups because all participating teams are neighbors and should improve their games together instead of committing faults or injuring each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AFF Championship and the love for football that unites people</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/aff-championship-love-for-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/aff-championship-love-for-football/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The biennial &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.affmitsubishielectriccup.com/2022/&#34;&gt;ASEAN Football Federation (AFF) Championship in 2022&lt;/a&gt; has started its first semi-final leg with a draw between Indonesia and Vietnam yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a tense match with both teams unable to score in front of about 50,000 spectators in Gelora Bung Karno Stadium. That is a huge turnout in a country severely affected by the Covid pandemic just 2 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They will meet again for the second leg on Monday at My Dinh stadium on Monday. Greeting the Indonesia team would be at least 30,000 home fans there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
