<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Gerald Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Gerald Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Behavior Driven Development (BDD) with Selenium in Python</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2024/05/behavior-driven-development-bdd-with-selenium-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2024/05/behavior-driven-development-bdd-with-selenium-in-python/</guid>
      <description>This is a continuation from my previous article where we learned the basic of Selenium and how to program it in Python to perform UI automation testing.&#xA;Getting started on UI automation testing using Selenium with Python&#xA;Five Minimum Viable Interview Questions series — Updated 17 Feb 2023 Interviewer: ask them if your interview is running out of time. Interviewee: practice them if your preparation is running out of time. Basics of BDD Behavior Driven Development is a popular software development discipline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOLID in Action: the Dependency Inversion Principle</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2023/02/solid-dependency-inversion-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2023/02/solid-dependency-inversion-principle/</guid>
      <description>Photo by ocd studio on Unsplash&#xA;The Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP) Naive application of traditional software development methods (e.g. SADT or Structured Analysis and Design Technique), in the past, often resulted in a type of relationship where high-level modules depended on lower implementation details. This form of relationship often leads to rigidity, fragility, and immobility. These are the symptoms of bad design according to Robert C. Martin.&#xA;A naive application of top-down approaches can lead to bad design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Minimum Viable Interview Questions series — Updated 17 Feb 2023</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2023/02/five-minimum-viable-interview-questions-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2023/02/five-minimum-viable-interview-questions-series/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Wes Hicks on Unsplash&#xA;Rationale Let’s face it. A developer is expected to know A LOT these days.&#xA;A typical job requirement (screenshot)&#xA;And that makes interviewing a candidate hard because there is never enough time to ask all the necessary questions.&#xA;On the other hand, that also makes preparing for an interview hard because there are too many areas and details to prepare for.&#xA;These are in fact the very challenges I faced every time I apply for a new job, or interview to hire a new team member.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOLID in Action: the Interface Segregation Principle</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2023/01/solid-interface-segregation-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2023/01/solid-interface-segregation-principle/</guid>
      <description>Photos by Eugen Str on Unsplash&#xA;Photos by Patrick on Unsplash&#xA;If you are going to build a house, a table, or a chair, what is your preferred option? The multiple tools on the first picture or one Swiss knife on the second?&#xA;Yep, you are right. If you want to create something useful that last for years, you need specialized tools. The same thinking applies to software development, if you want to create a serious application, you need specialized components represented by their own, purposely designed interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOLID in Action — the Liskov Substitution Principle</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2023/01/solid-liskov-substitution-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2023/01/solid-liskov-substitution-principle/</guid>
      <description>Let us start with a question:&#xA;Can social media connections substitute for real life friends and family?&#xA;Well, it depends on how we define &amp;ldquo;connection&amp;rdquo;. If we have it as below, then according to the Liskow Substitution Principle (LSP), the answer is No.&#xA;Connection classes&#xA;Before we go further into this example, let’s back it up a bit to study the official definition of LSP.&#xA;There is some math but I promise to keep it brief</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retry WebClient Request</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/retry-webclient-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/retry-webclient-request/</guid>
      <description>Problem Statement Sometimes web request fails, for whatever reason, and you need to retry it&#xA;Let’s simulate a failed request scenario in a unit test. In the below code, the webClient attempts to submit a GET request to /employee/100 (stored in constant PATH). We mocked the backend server to fail with common status codes such as BAD_REQUEST, UNAUTHORIZED and validate that the client throws WebClientResponseException upon receiving such statuses.&#xA;@ParameterizedTest @EnumSource(value = HttpStatus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Programmer to Writer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/from-programmer-to-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/from-programmer-to-writer/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Glenn Carstens-Peters on Unsplash&#xA;I’m a programmer by trade and write codes for a living. Then 1 month ago, I decided to become a writer. Here are the reasons why I did it and how I do it.&#xA;I’m pursuing my hobby I never considered writing a hobby. I barely managed to pass my literature and English classes. I preferred subjects that did not require writing such as Mathematics, Chemistry, or Physics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple Code — Effective UI — Month Picker</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/simple-code-effective-ui-month-picker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/simple-code-effective-ui-month-picker/</guid>
      <description>Option 1: separate Month and Year dropdowns Separate month and year dropdowns&#xA;It may be verbose, but you have total control over their placements, label, and format&#xA;&amp;lt;select&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;January&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;February&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;March&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;April&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;May&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;June&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;July&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;August&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;September&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;October&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;November&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;December&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/select&amp;gt; Month &amp;lt;select&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;2021&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;2022&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;option&amp;gt;2023&amp;lt;/option&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/select&amp;gt; Year Option 2: use the browser’s built-in month picker Built-in month picker&#xA;You have less control over the picker’s appearance, but the code is much cleaner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The best way to fix Hibernate’s MultipleBagFetchException</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/fixing-hibernate-multiplebagfetchexception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2022/12/fixing-hibernate-multiplebagfetchexception/</guid>
      <description>There are 2 articles from https://vladmihalcea.com describing his analysis and solutions to Hibernate’s MultipleBagFetchException. The first one, appeared around 2020 (when I first researched this problem) or even earlier (2018?), offered an analysis of the problem and a solution using Hibernate’s EntityManager API. The second one appeared around Jun 2022, and offers a slightly different solution for JPA.&#xA;I will present below my understanding of his analysis, his solutions, and working sample codes which you can check out and validate your understanding and/or devise your own solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unit testing Java’s try-with-resource</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2022/11/unit-testing-java-try-with-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2022/11/unit-testing-java-try-with-resource/</guid>
      <description>Java’s try-with-resource is a convenient syntactic shortcut. It frees developers from keeping track of closeable resources and closing in a finally block&#xA;Unit testing try-with-resource&#xA;Overview Some of us may remember doing such boring and lengthy try-finally-if-not-null-close() A LOT!&#xA;On a typical day, we performed these steps a dozen times:&#xA;Obtained a DB connection, and execute a query within the try {...} And then, to avoid connection leak, we must close the statement and DB connection within the finally {.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Bootstrap with React</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2020/04/2020-04-20-using-bootstrap-with-react/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2020/04/2020-04-20-using-bootstrap-with-react/</guid>
      <description>Mixing browser and React Insert links to Bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s javascript and CSS and its dependencies in app&amp;rsquo;s index.html&#xA;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;stylesheet&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;https://stackpath.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/4.4.1/css/bootstrap.min.css&amp;#34; integrity=&amp;#34;sha384-Vkoo8x4CGsO3+Hhxv8T/Q5PaXtkKtu6ug5TOeNV6gBiFeWPGFN9MuhOf23Q9Ifjh&amp;#34; crossorigin=&amp;#34;anonymous&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- other content --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://stackpath.bootstrapcdn.com/bootstrap/4.4.1/js/bootstrap.min.js&amp;#34; integrity=&amp;#34;sha384-wfSDF2E50Y2D1uUdj0O3uMBJnjuUD4Ih7YwaYd1iqfktj0Uod8GCExl3Og8ifwB6&amp;#34; crossorigin=&amp;#34;anonymous&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://code.jquery.com/jquery-3.4.1.slim.min.js&amp;#34; integrity=&amp;#34;sha384-J6qa4849blE2+poT4WnyKhv5vZF5SrPo0iEjwBvKU7imGFAV0wwj1yYfoRSJoZ+n&amp;#34; crossorigin=&amp;#34;anonymous&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/popper.js@1.16.0/dist/umd/popper.min.js&amp;#34; integrity=&amp;#34;sha384-Q6E9RHvbIyZFJoft+2mJbHaEWldlvI9IOYy5n3zV9zzTtmI3UksdQRVvoxMfooAo&amp;#34; crossorigin=&amp;#34;anonymous&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; Invoke appropriate method via window.$ jQuery object&#xA;window.$(&amp;#39;#about-modal&amp;#39;).modal() Pure React way Install Bootstrap as a NPM module&#xA;npm install bootstrap --save npm install jquery popper.js --save Load bootstrap CSS and Javascript in React app&amp;rsquo;s entry point (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Excel] Bulk Linking Cells to Sheets Whose Name Equates Cell&#39;s value</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2013/12/2013-12-30-bulk-linking-cell-to-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2013/12/2013-12-30-bulk-linking-cell-to-sheets/</guid>
      <description>Sub CreateLinkToSheet() Dim c As Range For Each c In Selection &amp;#39; MsgBox c.Value ActiveSheet.Hyperlinks.Add Anchor:=c, Address:=&amp;#34;&amp;#34;, _ SubAddress:=c.Value &amp;amp; &amp;#34;!A1&amp;#34;, TextToDisplay:=c.Value Next c End Sub How to run: Select the cells to create link and run the macro</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[VBA] Save Attachements from Multiple Emails</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2013/09/2013-09-02-save-attachments-from-multiple-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2013/09/2013-09-02-save-attachments-from-multiple-emails/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisite: Enable Developer tab, macro security and create “C:\mailattachment\” folder if not exists&#xA;Instruction: Select emails which have attachment to save (e.g. email containing daily report), select Developer, Macro, SaveAttachment&#xA;Sub SaveAttachment() Dim myOlapp As Outlook.Application Dim myNameSpace As Outlook.NameSpace Dim myFolder As Outlook.MAPIFolder Dim myItem As Outlook.MailItem Dim myAttachment As Outlook.Attachment Dim I As Long Set myOlapp = CreateObject(&amp;#34;Outlook.Application&amp;#34;) &amp;#39;Set myNameSpace = myOlapp.GetNamespace(&amp;#34;MAPI&amp;#34;) &amp;#39;Set myFolder = myNameSpace.GetDefaultFolder(olFolderInbox) &amp;#39;Set myFolder = myFolder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[Database] Exists or Inner Join: Duplicate Records</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2013/06/2013-06-16-database-exist-or-inner-join-duplicate-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2013/06/2013-06-16-database-exist-or-inner-join-duplicate-transactions/</guid>
      <description>INNER JOIN vs. EXISTS Often, EXISTS and INNER JOIN can be used interchangeably to query data with existence in 2 or more tables. However, it is not always the case. There is an important inherent characteristics of INNER JOIN that every developer should keep in mind: INNER JOIN result may contain DUPLICATE data record. This is important for uniqueness-sensitive handling of query result (e.g. record count), or when migrating database table with unique constraints.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Form of String Comparison Is Supported</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2013/05/2013-05-21-which-form-of-string-comparison-is-supported/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2013/05/2013-05-21-which-form-of-string-comparison-is-supported/</guid>
      <description>Below example is for Oracle DB, but adopting for other DBMS e.g. Sybase, MS SQL… should be straightforward.&#xA;select ‘both no space’ as “String comparison in Oracle” from dual where ‘a’ = ‘a’ -- union select ‘right has single trailing space’ from dual where ‘a’ = ‘a ‘ union select ‘right has multiple trailing space’ from dual where ‘a’ = ‘a ‘ union select ‘right has single leading space’ from dual where ‘a’ = ‘ a’ union select ‘right has multiple leading space’ from dual where ‘a’ = ‘ a’ -- union select ‘left has single trailing space’ from dual where ‘a ‘ = ‘a’ union select ‘left has multiple trailing space’ from dual where ‘a ‘ = ‘a’ union select ‘left has single leading space’ from dual where ‘ a’ = ‘a’ union select ‘left has multiple leading space’ from dual where ‘ a’ = ‘a’ -- union select ‘right has single leading and trailing space’ from dual where ‘a’ = ‘ a ‘ union select ‘right has multiple leading and trailing space’ from dual where ‘a’ = ‘ a ‘ union select ‘left has single leading and trailing space’ from dual where ‘ a ‘ = ‘a’ union select ‘left has multiple leading and trailing space’ from dual where ‘ a ‘ = ‘a’ —- union select ‘both has leading and trailing space but leading space are different’ from dual where ‘ a ‘ = ‘ a ‘ </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do you initialize an EJB3 Stateful Session Bean ?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/2010/11/2010-11-10-initialize-ejb3-stateful-session-bean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/2010/11/2010-11-10-initialize-ejb3-stateful-session-bean/</guid>
      <description>In EJB 3, we can obtain a reference to Stateful Session Bean either either by using @EJB annotation or performing JNDI look-up. Yet these 2 methods do not offer you a way to initialize a Stateful SB as EJB 2.1 Home interface&amp;rsquo;s createMETHODs do.&#xA;StatefulSB bean = home.create (arg0, arg1, arg2); EJB3 defines @Init annotation as a replacement for EJB 2.1 createMETHOD. But it is intended for bean written to 2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
