<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medium on Gerald Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/tags/medium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medium on Gerald Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 09:19:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://geraldnguyen.github.io/tags/medium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Displaying Quotes the Medium styles</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2024/08/hugo-block-quote-pull-quote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2024/08/hugo-block-quote-pull-quote/</guid>
      <description>Please ignore the \ in front of { in code examples. It is used to prevent Hugo from processing the shortcodes even in code block&#xA;The Block Quote This is a block quote&#xA;&amp;gt; This is a block quote The Pull Quote We need a custom quote.html shortcode and some custom CSS&#xA;The quote shortcode:&#xA;# quote.html {{$quote := .Get 0}} &amp;lt;blockquote class=&amp;#34;medium-quote&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; {{ markdownify $quote }} {{ markdownify .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hugo - Displaying Images the Medium way</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2024/08/hugo-displaying-images-the-medium-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2024/08/hugo-displaying-images-the-medium-way/</guid>
      <description>Please ignore the \ in front of { in code examples. It is used to prevent Hugo from processing the shortcodes even in code block&#xA;The Markdown way ![alt title](1_nHC2UMz-xJM-lvPPwSh_vQ.webp) Though it is recommended, the alt-title is optional. The above can be expressed as ![alt title](path-to-image.jpg)&#xA;Pros:&#xA;Simple Natively markdown Cons:&#xA;No caption Center alignment not guaranteed The Medium way {{\&amp;lt; figure src=&amp;#34;1_nHC2UMz-xJM-lvPPwSh_vQ.webp&amp;#34; caption=&amp;#34;optional caption&amp;#34; \&amp;gt;}} optional caption&#xA;Pros:&#xA;Support caption, plain text and markdown Center alignment Cons:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#STYOut or #STYSTAY — What is better for Indonesian Football?</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/styout-stystay-what-is-better-for-indonesian-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/styout-stystay-what-is-better-for-indonesian-football/</guid>
      <description>Source: https://zingnews.vn/&#xA;The Garuda team lost 0–2 to the Golden Dragon team on Monday, thus failing to reach the AFF Mitsubishi Electric Cup’s final. For a team from a football-crazed Indonesia, the loss was heartbreaking for many.&#xA;Some took to social media calling for the sacking of coach Shin Tae-Yong. The tag #STYOut has been trending among Indonesian fans. Some were calmer. They defended him. #STYSTAY has been trending as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AFF Championship and the love for football that unites people</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/aff-championship-love-for-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/aff-championship-love-for-football/</guid>
      <description>The biennial ASEAN Football Federation (AFF) Championship in 2022 has started its first semi-final leg with a draw between Indonesia and Vietnam yesterday.&#xA;It was a tense match with both teams unable to score in front of about 50,000 spectators in Gelora Bung Karno Stadium. That is a huge turnout in a country severely affected by the Covid pandemic just 2 years ago.&#xA;They will meet again for the second leg on Monday at My Dinh stadium on Monday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Home Deity is Not Divine</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/the-home-deity-is-not-divine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/the-home-deity-is-not-divine/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Chinh Le Duc on Unsplash&#xA;The title is loosely translated from a Vietnamese idiom&#xA;Bụt chùa nhà không thiêng Literally translated, the idiom is about a Buddhist Saint (Vietnamese: bụt) prayed to in a pagoda (Vietnamese: chùa) close to or within the home (Vietnamese: nhà) being non-divine (Vietnamese: không thiêng)&#xA;Usages The idiom has 2 common usages. One is a resignation that own advice, tool, resource, etc… was unsuccessful in helping a close friend, a loved one, or a fond organization achieves an objective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writers, please go to sleep earlier</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/writers-please-go-to-sleep-earlier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/writers-please-go-to-sleep-earlier/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Brett Jordan on Unsplash&#xA;Brace yourselves. Holidays are ending I am determined to become a writer. That does not mean forgoing my day job. Once back to work, I will be away from Medium for about 13 hours straights (8 AM to 9 PM). Writings only resume at night or during weekends.&#xA;I experienced some of that reality these past 2 weeks. I had cleared my annual leaves in early December to “avoid the crowd”, so I worked the last week of December while most colleagues were away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regional economic development in Vietnam — Reform &amp; “Reorder”</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/regional-economic-development-in-vietnam-reform-reorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/regional-economic-development-in-vietnam-reform-reorder/</guid>
      <description>35 years of Đổi Mới (Economic Reform) helped Vietnam from a country that had to “run for rice” (see note 1) in the early 1980s to become a middle-income country, reaching the top 20 of the world’s leading economies in terms of international trade. The Reform has turned many poor rural areas into industrial districts, farmers into city dwellers, the number of poor households has decreased sharply, the middle class has increased rapidly… But the Reform process also led to the “Reorder” among provinces and regions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The story of the drums in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/the-story-of-the-drums-in-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/the-story-of-the-drums-in-singapore/</guid>
      <description>Many times when I visited Singapore, I noticed that under each apartment building, there were 2–3 red-painted drums in a straight line. These drums are modified with ventilation holes, have high legs, and have discharge doors… so that when households need to burn votive paper, they can do it here.&#xA;Incense burner (source: author’s father)&#xA;In a country where more than 70% of the population is Chinese with the tradition and custom of burning votive papers a lot every Lunar New Year, anniversaries, funerals, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Programmer to Writer</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/from-programmer-to-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/from-programmer-to-writer/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Glenn Carstens-Peters on Unsplash&#xA;I’m a programmer by trade and write codes for a living. Then 1 month ago, I decided to become a writer. Here are the reasons why I did it and how I do it.&#xA;I’m pursuing my hobby I never considered writing a hobby. I barely managed to pass my literature and English classes. I preferred subjects that did not require writing such as Mathematics, Chemistry, or Physics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singapore: City in a Garden</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/singapore-city-in-a-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/singapore-city-in-a-garden/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Kirill Petropavlov on Unsplash&#xA;What is worth learning from the Lion island nation is, first of all, the strategic vision of development and the solution to turn that vision into reality.&#xA;The goal is to continuously improve people’s quality of life&#xA;From the perspective of urban development, Singapore is considered to have a very good level of urban planning and management. With an area only slightly larger than Vietnam’s Phu Quoc island, a population of 5.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
