<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Translation on Gerald Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/tags/translation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Translation on Gerald Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://geraldnguyen.github.io/tags/translation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Home Deity is Not Divine</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/the-home-deity-is-not-divine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2023/01/the-home-deity-is-not-divine/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Chinh Le Duc on Unsplash&#xA;The title is loosely translated from a Vietnamese idiom&#xA;Bụt chùa nhà không thiêng Literally translated, the idiom is about a Buddhist Saint (Vietnamese: bụt) prayed to in a pagoda (Vietnamese: chùa) close to or within the home (Vietnamese: nhà) being non-divine (Vietnamese: không thiêng)&#xA;Usages The idiom has 2 common usages. One is a resignation that own advice, tool, resource, etc… was unsuccessful in helping a close friend, a loved one, or a fond organization achieves an objective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regional economic development in Vietnam — Reform &amp; “Reorder”</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/regional-economic-development-in-vietnam-reform-reorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/regional-economic-development-in-vietnam-reform-reorder/</guid>
      <description>35 years of Đổi Mới (Economic Reform) helped Vietnam from a country that had to “run for rice” (see note 1) in the early 1980s to become a middle-income country, reaching the top 20 of the world’s leading economies in terms of international trade. The Reform has turned many poor rural areas into industrial districts, farmers into city dwellers, the number of poor households has decreased sharply, the middle class has increased rapidly… But the Reform process also led to the “Reorder” among provinces and regions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The story of the drums in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/the-story-of-the-drums-in-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/the-story-of-the-drums-in-singapore/</guid>
      <description>Many times when I visited Singapore, I noticed that under each apartment building, there were 2–3 red-painted drums in a straight line. These drums are modified with ventilation holes, have high legs, and have discharge doors… so that when households need to burn votive paper, they can do it here.&#xA;Incense burner (source: author’s father)&#xA;In a country where more than 70% of the population is Chinese with the tradition and custom of burning votive papers a lot every Lunar New Year, anniversaries, funerals, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singapore: City in a Garden</title>
      <link>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/singapore-city-in-a-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 09:19:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://geraldnguyen.github.io/posts/2022/12/singapore-city-in-a-garden/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Kirill Petropavlov on Unsplash&#xA;What is worth learning from the Lion island nation is, first of all, the strategic vision of development and the solution to turn that vision into reality.&#xA;The goal is to continuously improve people’s quality of life&#xA;From the perspective of urban development, Singapore is considered to have a very good level of urban planning and management. With an area only slightly larger than Vietnam’s Phu Quoc island, a population of 5.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
